Personal Papers of Lester Nurick
World Bank Group Archives
- Chronological correspondence, 1946 - 2004; WB IBRD/IDA NURICK-01; 5.81 linear feet of textual records
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) Chronological File - January 1961 to December 1961, 1961-01-01 - 1961-12-31; 30044990
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) Chronological File - January 1960 to December 1960, 1960-01-01 - 1960-12-31; 30044989
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) Chronological File - January 1959 to December 1960, 1959-01-01 - 1960-12-31; 30044988
  - International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) Chronological File - January 1959 to December 1959, 1959-01-01 - 1959-12-31; 30044987
  - International Finance Corporation (IFC) Chronological File - January 1958 to December 1958, 1958-01-01 - 1958-12-31; 30044926
  - International Finance Corporation (IFC) Chronological File - August 1957 to December 1957, 1957-08-01 - 1957-12-31; 30044925
  - International Finance Corporation (IFC) Chronological File - January 1957 to July 1957, 1957-01-01 - 1957-07-31; 30044924
  - International Finance Corporation (IFC) Chronological File - January 1956 to December 1956, 1956-01-01 - 1956-12-31; 30044923
  - International Finance Corporation (IFC) Chronological File - July 1955 to December 1956, 1955-07-01 - 1956-12-31; 30044922
  - Chronological File - June 1954 to December 1955, 1954-06-01 - 1955-12-31; 30044921
  - Chronological File - June 1953 to June 1954, 1953-06-01 - 1954-06-30; 30044920
  - Chronological File - May 1952 to May 1953, 1952-05-01 - 1953-05-31; 30044919
  - Chronological File - April 1951 to April 1952, 1951-04-01 - 1952-04-30; 30044918
  - Chronological File - October 1946 to January 1949, 1946-10-01 - 1949-01-31; 30044917
- Collection of published materials and mementos, 1950 - 1990; WB IBRD/IDA NURICK-02; 0.40 linear feet of textual records; 1 photograph
  Series contains published materials and other items related to Lurick's work at the World Bank Group. Materials appear to have been selected by Nurick as personal mementos. Included are fourteen copies of the Bank's in-house staff publication International Bank Notes that contain mention of Nurick and his work or celebrate various anniversaries of the Bank. Also included are three copies of an IBRD Office of Information's press clippings compilation from May 1959 in which Nurick is mentioned. Materials related to a trip Nurick made to Japan in 1971 are included as are invitations for Nurick's attendance at a variety of events. Finally, an inscribed copy of a personal memoir by Bank colleague Davidson Sommers titled "Recollections" is included in this series.
  - IBRD Office of Information - Press clippings - No. 17, May 6, 1959 (3 copies), 1959-05-06; 30297709
  - Publication - "Recollections" by Davidson Sommers, 1990-01-01 - 1990-12-31; 30297708
  - Miscellaneous invitations, 1958-01-01 - 1962-12-31; 30297707
  - IBRD Information Bulletin - Vol. III Nos. 41 and 43; Vol. V No. 6, 1950-01-01 - 1952-12-31; 30297705
  - Japan - Photograph, newspaper clipping, and gift, 1971-01-01 - 1971-12-31; 30297703
  - International Bank Notes - Various, 1950-01-01 - 1962-12-31; 30297718